# Olha Klymas

Calgary, AB

olhaklymas@gmail.com; linkedin.com/in/olha-klymas-6182a415b; portfolio - olha.klymas.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I have been engaged in frontend development for more than 4 years, I have strong skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and TypeScript. I have experience working with the VUE framework, and I also know REACT. I have worked on SalesForce Commerce Cloud (Demandware) projects and have experience with Storefront Reference Architecture (SFRA).

I have got a visa CUAET and a work permit. So I can start work as soon as I arrive in your town.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Raccoon LLC, Vinnytsia, Ukraine

04/2022 - Present

Middle SFCC Frontend Developer

I have experience with Storefront Reference Architecture (SFRA).

The main technologies we are using are HTML, SCSS, and JavaScript (seldom jQuery).

Took part on developing several SalesForce Commerce Cloud (Demandware) projects as part of the different teams:

- updating styles for different components and pages;
- modifying and configuring content-asset assets and slots;
- setting up Page Designer pages;
- creating templates for email letters;
- writing technical documentation.

#### IT Education Academy, Kyiv, Ukraine

10/2021 - Present

Front End Development Teacher

I am teaching courses in HTML&CSS, JavaScript Base and JavaScript Advanced. I have graduated more than 80 students and more of them became Junior Frontend Developers. Some students got their first work in IT during studying or the first month after the course ended. With several graduated students, we are keeping in touch and they share their successes.

Since last October, I am taking part in the project <u>IT Generation</u> of the Ministry of Digital Transformation in Ukraine and partners. It helps Ukrainians to be able to get a new qualification free. I have graduated 24 students with this project.

<u>Sun Agency</u>, Kyiv, Ukraine 09/2021 – 03/2022

Front End Developer

- developed new pages on one of the popular online stores in Ukraine;
- implemented Visicom API to get customer addresses using the map;
- took participation in the development of the site using the Vue framework;
- made restyling existing pages, according to the new design in Figma.

# Consult.marketing, Brovary, Ukraine

10/2018 - 09/2021

Front End Developer

- developed various online stores and landing pages using WordPress CMS, Opencart according to the requirements;
- implemented Plektan CRM system (for realtors) via the REST API;
- used WP REST API to implement filters and post pages;
- applied different plugins to CMS WordPress like Elementor, Woocommerce, Advanced custom fields, Ajax search for woocommerce etc.

### **EDUCATION**

# IT Education Academy, Kyiv, Ukraine

2017 - 2020

Passed courses:

- HTML&CSS
- JavaScript
- Vue
- React

#### National University of State Tax Service of Ukraine, Irpin, Ukraine

2011 - 2013

Master degree of Finance and credit

**Technical Skills:** HTML, CSS, SCSS (SASS), JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, Webpack, Gulp, Bootstrap, WordPress, Opencart, Figma, Jira, Slack.

Languages: English level – Intermediate and fluent in Ukrainian